<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>EVA</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.evaimg.org/</id><updated>2013-12-13T11:27:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Powerful intensity profile tool!</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/powerful-waveform-display.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-13T11:27:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-12-13:blog/powerful-waveform-display.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Intensity profile is important&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the first intensity profile tool for Icy is developed, improvement is never stoped, the reason is that this kind of tool is useful to 1D signal based image data. Sample point of 1D signal is displayed as image pixel, but we have get used to the waveform mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, some large scale improvement is made to IntensityInRectangle plugin. Here is some useful feature of the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show any number of profiles simutaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distinguish roi pairs with different color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profile canvas can be resized and operated just like a rectangle ROI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a cursor line to indicate mouse position, update in realtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support line, point, rectangle and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Modes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Line Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Line Mode, profile of the current image is calculated along the line roi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Point Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there is only one point, so the profile is calcualted along Z axis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Area Mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All othe type of ROI except line and point is manipulated under this mode, in Area Mode, intensity profile is calculated along Z axis but the mean intensity of each Z layer is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more detail about the IntensityInRectangle plugins, see [Download][../pages/downloads].&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category></entry><entry><title>Machine learning plugin for Icy</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/rapid-learning.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-17T22:40:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-11-17:blog/rapid-learning.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to RapidMiner(formerly YALE) , which is a powerful and intuitive data mining tool implemented in Java and available under GPL (GNU General Public License).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plugin, Rapid Learning, brings the power of RapidMiner to Icy, enables infinite probability, you can do all kinds things such as data loading and transformation (Extract, transform, load, a.k.a. ETL), data preprocessing and visualisation, modelling, evaluation, and deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rapid Learning plugin, dimensions of (Z,T and C) are treated as features, packaged as an ExampleSet, the ExampleSet then can be used for training and predicting in RapidMiner process. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, you can do supervised learning and unsupervised learning to sequence. In supervised learning, you need to define some labels in Mask Editor and draw then on your sequence, then you can train your data and do predicting to other data. You also can do unsupervised learning like clustering, you will use Mask Editor to define your training set and then you can train the model and predicting other sequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you should download RapidMiner first and put the "lib" folder into "plugins" of Icy. Maybe I should make another plugin to include RapidMiner, but the package is too big to a icy library and I should find some way to enables the user use it as a standalone software.
You may also need the example process file needed by the plugin in the attachments. You can find some more information in the plugin page, about how to use them and how to generate it by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it's a preview edition, it works under my tests, there still many work to do,so suggestions are highly appreciated.
Welcome to have a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="RapidLearningPlugin" src="http://i.imgur.com/kGPOzoR.png?1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more detail about the plugins, see &lt;a href="http://icy.bioimageanalysis.org/plugin/Rapid_Learning"&gt;Rapid Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category><category term="machine_learning"></category></entry><entry><title>Surface tracking plugin for Icy</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/pixel-row-align.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-12T07:40:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-10-12:blog/pixel-row-align.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immersion testing is one of the most common method in Ultrasonic testing. A technology named "surface tracking" always used in immersion testing. By finding the first echo of the whole sequence of wave, we can get the echo of the liquid-specimen interface. With the offset of the interface, we can inspect the status of the surface, or we can align all the echoes to the same time position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;pixelRowAlign plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest method to achieve this goal is using a simple threshold to find the interface echo position. We have implement a plugin named "pixelRowAlign". With this plugin, you will able to find the echo by defining a threshold, you can choose differenet stratage to find the echoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="pixelRowAlignPlugin" src="http://i.imgur.com/YGQABo6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more detail about the plugins, see &lt;a href="../pages/downloads"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category><category term="ultrasonic"></category></entry><entry><title>Hardware connection with Micro-Manager</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/micro-manager-for-icy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-27T10:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-09-27:blog/micro-manager-for-icy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Hardware solutions for EVA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micro-manager is a powerful framework for hardware integration, is a ideal solution for EVA project to support hardwares. Micro-manager is used to support all kinds of microscopies and accessories by providing a flexiable driver adapter machanisim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For EVA project itself, we trying to include some open source hardware in order to build less-pricy research platform. We decide to use Micro-manager as a midware to bridge the hardware and the Icy software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another reason is, Micro-Manager is fully supported in Icy, we got "Micro-Manager for Icy" and many other plugins can work with Micro-Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Micro-Manager, all kinds of data can be represent as image. Signals in 1D can also treated as a one-row image, and the value range can be 8 bit to 64 bit, so it can represent almost every kind of signal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will demostrate this framework with a ultrasonic imaging device.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category></entry><entry><title>Plugin to show 1D signal in Icy is out!</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/1d-signal-chart-canvas.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-04T10:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-07-04:blog/1d-signal-chart-canvas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;1D signal representation in Icy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, I mentioned there is no elegant way to show 1D signal in Icy, although 1D signal takes the most part NDT/NDE signal such as Ultrasonic, Eddy Current. Many imaging method is based on the analysis of 1D signal. For an instance, we should find the back wall echo in order to generate a simple C-Scan map.
So show 1D signal as waveform is very important in a NDE system. But the previous method to do this is tedious, since we should put our profile line on the right position and should adjust two frames to get a better view. Operation in two frames makes the manipulation more complicated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Canvas plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is "Canvas", thanks Fabrice and Stephane. There is a mechanism called "Canvas" which is used for different type of representation of data. When you open a sequence in Icy, it will open in 2D canvas by default. And also you can shift different canvas on the top of the sequence window, for example you can expand your z-axis to make a montage view of your 3D data. Another good news is "Canvas" is supported in plugin developing. Then a Canvas Plugin will become an elegant way to extend Icy to support 1D signal representation.
What's more, Icy itself have Jfreechart integrated in its library, which helps a lot when dealing with 1D signal GUI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Plugin -- Chart1DCanvas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some coding work, I finally implemented a canvas plugin named &lt;a href="http://icy.bioimageanalysis.org/plugin/Chart1DCanvas"&gt;Chart1DCanvas&lt;/a&gt; which can actually do the 1d signal representation work. This plugin will be act as a basis to the following NDE applications.
Here goes a screen shot of the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chart1DCanvas screen shot" src="../images/chart1dscreen.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this plugin, Icy will show a 1d signal in native way which actually is canvas.
We can use the canvas to show all kinds of waveforms such as eddy current and ultrasonic etc.. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See more detail about the plugins, see [Download][../pages/downloads].&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category><category term="ultrasonic"></category></entry><entry><title>1D signal presentation in Icy</title><link href="http://www.evaimg.org/blog/1d-signal-presentation.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-30T21:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:www.evaimg.org,2013-06-30:blog/1d-signal-presentation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Icy is designed for 2D+ image data processing, but in NDE, we often get 1D signal like ultrasonic waveform. The following picture shows a sample of typical ultrasonic waveform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ultrasonic waveform" src="../images/ultrasonicWave.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are a lot of plugins available on the Icy repository, and a user can alway find something they want. So I found the "Intensity Profile" plugin which can used a a temporary solution to show a waveform in Icy.
The following picture shows the screen shot of using intensity profile to show a waveform stored as a picture with only one row pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="1-Row Image With Intensity Profile" src="../images/CaptureOfIcyGUI.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage:
1. Input "IntensityProfile" in the search bar of Icy, it located in the upper left of the main window. When it appears in the search result, just click to install.
2. Open you image, we can store a waveform as a row of pixels, which also means one pixels is one sample value from your data acquisition device. Don't care much about the data range, Icy supports 32-bit gray image, which will be enough for most ADC device.
3. Then put a line ROI on the image, adjust it to the right position, you can press shift key to make it orthogonal.
4. Click "IntensityProfile" in the menu bar. And you will see a cure displayed in a chart window. You can zoom in and out, the chart is handled by a java chart library known as "JfreeChart".&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category><category term="ultrasonic"></category></entry></feed>