<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>EVA-NDE</title><link href="http://oeway.github.io/EVA-NDE/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://oeway.github.io/EVA-NDE/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://oeway.github.io/EVA-NDE/</id><updated>2013-06-30T21:30:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>1D signal presentation in Icy</title><link href="http://oeway.github.io/EVA-NDE/blog/2013-6-24.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-30T21:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Will Ouyang</name></author><id>tag:oeway.github.io/EVA-NDE,2013-06-30:blog/2013-6-24.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Icy is designed for 2D+ image data processing, but in NDE, we often get 1D signal like ultrasonic waveform. The following picture shows a sample of typical ultrasonic waveform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ultrasonic waveform" src="/static/images/ultrasonicWave.JPG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we want to process 1d signal, or acquisite 1d signal in Micro-Manager within Icy, we need to figure out some way to presente 1d signal in Icy.
Icy itself have Jfreechart included in its library, and there also some plugins like &lt;a href="http://icy.bioimageanalysis.org/plugin/Intensity_Profile"&gt;Intensity Profile&lt;/a&gt; can draw a profile of a line of pixel intensity.
So a intuitive idea is acqusite the 1d signal as a 1-row image using Micro-Manager for Icy plugin and then plot the intensity profile of the 1-row image. The following image demostrate this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="1-Row Image With Intensity Profile" src="/static/images/CaptureOfIcyGUI.PNG" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Plugin -- Chart1DCanvas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following this idea, I fired &lt;a href=""&gt;a thread&lt;/a&gt; in the forum of Icy. Then I got some suggestions from Fabrice and Stephane. After some coding work, I finally implemented a canvas plugin named &lt;a href="http://icy.bioimageanalysis.org/plugin/Chart1DCanvas"&gt;Chart1DCanvas&lt;/a&gt; which can actually do the 1d signal representation work. This plugin will be act as a basis to the following NDE applications.
Here goes a screen shot of the plugin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Chart1DCanvas screen shot" src="/static/images/chart1dscreen.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this plugin, Icy will show a 1d signal in native way which actually is canvas.
We can use the canvas to show all kinds of waveforms such as eddy current and ultrasonic etc.. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="plugin"></category><category term="ultrasonic"></category></entry></feed>